二零二一年广东省初中学业水平考试
英语试卷听力部分。
首先播放两分钟的音乐信号，请监考老师调试好播音设备的音量。
音乐结束后听。
一考试正式开始。
Please Please Please equipment.
equipment. Please equipment.
Please adjust Please adjust the equipment.
Please adjust equipment.
Please adjust Please adjust
Please Please Please Please
Please Please adjust the
Please adjust volume equipment.
Please adjust volume the adjust adjust
视听到此结束。
Please adjust equipment.
一、听力理解。
a. 1. My cousin is the man playing the piano over there.
听句子，根据所听内容
选择符合题意的图画，回答问题，并将答题卡上对应题目所选的选项涂黑
每小题听一遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒。
的答题时间。
2. There are two little birds over my bird house.
3. Jim was sent to the hospital after he was hit by a car.
4. Tom helps his mom clean the windows every weekend.
5. To get to the bank, take the second turning on the left.
b. See you on the 30th!
听对话，回答每段对话后面的问题，在每小题所给的三个选项中选出一个
最佳答案，并将答题卡上对应题目所选的选项涂黑。
每段对话。
听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
听第一段对。
话，回答第六小题。
听第二段对话，回答第七小题。
听第三段对话，回答第八小题。
听第四段对话。
卡，
听第五段对话，回答第十小题。
听第六段对话，回答第十一至十二小题。
听第七段对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
Aha! Here it says it eats flies.
I wish to have one at home.
Mary, look at this.
Scientists discovered this special plant last year.
Oh, a plant has big teeth?
That's quite strange.
And the teeth are as big as humans.
I think the plant can be very useful.
How? It looks so terrible.
Aha! Here it says it eats flies.
I wish to have one at home.
C. Betty has two little cats.
听短文，请根据。
据所听内容，在每小题所给出的三个选项中选出一个能完成句子的最佳答
案，并将答题卡上对应题目所选的选项涂黑。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读。
读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
听第一篇短文，回答第十六至二十小题。
现在你有二十五秒钟的读题时间
Her parents bought them as a birthday gift for her in a pet shop.
They were little and cute when she got them.
Several days later, she noticed something wrong with one of the cats.
It wouldn't eat or drink.
Betty was worried.
She called the The seller told her perhaps it got sick.
There was nothing he could do.
He suggested Betty take the cat to an animal hospital.
Betty followed his advice.
A doctor at the hospital checked the cat and said it had a stomach problem.
The doctor helped the cat take some medicine.
The next day, the little cat got well.
It jumped and ran as happily as the other little cat did.
Betty has two little cats.
Her parents bought them as a birthday gift for her in a pet shop.
They were little and cute when she got them.
Several days later, she noticed something wrong with one of the cats.
It wouldn't eat or drink.
Betty was worried.
She called the seller.
The seller told her perhaps it got sick.
There was nothing he could do.
He suggested Betty take the cat to an animal hospital.
Betty followed his advice.
A doctor at the hospital checked the cat and said it had a stomach problem.
The doctor helped the cat take some medicine.
The next day, the little cat got well.
It jumped and ran as happily as the other little cat did.
听第二篇短文，回答第二十一至二十五小题。
现在你有二十五秒钟的读题时间。
Good morning. Welcome to the 10 o 'clock program.
Today we are going to talk about hearing problems among young people.
Parents always tell their children to turn music down, but many of them just won't
listen. Scientists tested the hearing of 170 students last month.
The results showed that nearly 25
of them had pain in their ears.
The reason is that they often listen to loud music with earphones for a long time.
Earphones make music clearer and louder, but they are not good for the ears.
What can we do to protect our hearing?
Scientists suggested we use earphones for at most 60 minutes a day.
They also advised us to wear earplugs when going to rock concerts or working in a
noisy environment.
Thank you for listening to Road to Health.
See you next time.
Good morning. Welcome to the 10 o 'clock program.
Today we are going to talk about hearing problems among young people.
Parents always tell their children to turn music down, but many of them just won't
listen. Scientists tested the hearing of 170 students last month.
The results showed that nearly 25 of them had pain in their ears.
The reason is that they often listen to loud music with earphones for a long time.
The results showed to loud music showed The reason loud music with earphones for a
long time. The is often listen earphones earphones
1. card. question.
听填信息。
你将听到一则天气介绍，请你根据。
所听内容填写下面的信息卡，并将答案写在答题卡对应题目的答题位置上
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目；
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
have answer After you
After you have seconds
After 25 question.
After answer After answer
After you After you have answer Temperatures have been high these days.
Today's temperature has reached up to 35 degrees centigrade.
But here comes the good news.
We'll have rainy weather from tomorrow, Wednesday.
It means a break from hot days, and the rainy days will last until Sunday.
It will be cooler after the rain.
Everybody will feel good.
This could be bad news, though, because it also means no camping or going for a
picnic. In the second week of July, we are expecting two typhoons.
If you are going on holiday, you have to keep an eye on weather reports before the
holiday. Hello, everyone.
Summer has come.
Temperatures have been high these days.
Today's temperature has reached up to 35 degrees centigrade.
But here comes the good news.
We'll have rainy weather from tomorrow, Wednesday.
It means a break from hot days, and the rainy days will last until Sunday.
It will be cooler after the rain.
Everybody will feel good.
This could be bad news, though, because it also means no camping or going for a
picnic. In the second week of July, we are expecting two typhoons.
If you are going on holiday, you have to keep an eye on weather reports before the
holiday. bad news, though, because
听力考试到此结束。